Death has never been closer.
Final Destination 5 is a horror, mystery film directed by Steven Quale.
Death is just as omnipresent as ever, and is unleashed after one man’s premonition
saves a group of coworkers from a terrifying suspension bridge collapse.
But this group of unsuspecting souls was never supposed to survive, and, in a terrifying race against time,
the ill-fated group frantically tries to discover a way to escape Death’s sinister agenda.
Sam, played by Nicholas D'Agosto.
Molly, played by Emma Bell.
Peter Friedkin, played by Miles Fisher.
Candice Hooper, played by Ellen Wroe.
Olivia Castle, played by Jacqueline MacInnes Wood.
Isaac, played by P.J. Byrne.
Final Destination 5 is a 2011 American 3D supernatural horror film
directed by Steven Quale and written by Eric Heisserer.
It is the fifth installment in the Final Destination film
series and a prequel to Final Destination (2000).
Nicholas D'Agosto stars as a young man who has a premonition about a suspension bridge collapsing, and
saves a group of people from Death, only to learn that they cannot escape its plan.
Emma Bell, Miles Fisher, Arlen Escarpeta, David Koechner,
and Tony Todd star in supporting roles.
Despite The Final Destination (2009) being announced as the final film in the franchise, that film's
financial success led to the development of a fifth installment, which began in 2010.
Filming took place in Vancouver, as with the first three installments.
It is the second film in the franchise to be shot in 3D.
Final Destination 5 was theatrically released on August 12, 2011,
and on DVD on December 27, 2011, by Warner Bros.
Pictures and New Line Cinema.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $157 million worldwide,
becoming – as of May 2025 – the third highest-grossing film in the franchise.
A sixth film, Final Destination Bloodlines, was released in May 2025.
The film explores themes of premonition, accidental
death, crash, end is here, death.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.